Thomas Kiley

5 Redberry Court, Charlotte Street, Leamington Spa, CV31 3EB 07948284729 <u>t.kiley@warwick.ac.uk</u> <u>www.tkiley.co.uk</u>

I am a student in my final year, studying Discrete Mathematics at the University of Warwick. I am predicted to get a 1st class honours degree. I have 1.5 years industry experience, including an intercalated year at Born Ready Games (BRG). At BRG, I worked as a junior programmer and during this time we shipped Strike Suit Zero.

Skills

C#	Excellent	Numerous personal projects in addition to industry experience at doublesix
C++	Strong	1 year industry experience at Born Ready Games
Lua	Good	1 year industry experience in a supportive/debugging role
Java	Good	A number of personal projects including an Android app
Unity	Good	Many personal projects and game jams
UDK	Some experience	Used on game jams and explored in my own time

Education

University of Warwick 2010 - Present	BSc in Discrete Mathematics with Intercalated Year Predicted grade: 1st Class Honours Discrete Mathematics is a joint degree run by the Computer Science and Mathematics departments.
Guildford County School	A-Levels: Further Mathematics - A*; Computing - A*; Mathematics - A; Physics - B AS-Levels: History - A
2003-2010	9 GCSE's including A* in Maths and Science, 5 As (including French and Latin) and 2 Bs

Experience

Born Ready Games

July 2012 - July 2013 (Intercalated Year)

- Released Strike Suit Zero http://store.steampowered.com/app/209540
- Gained one year of industry experience using C++ within the context of the (in house) game engine.
- Refactored the save system to support multiple save files.
- Part of a team of two that ported the game over to the Mac and Linux, including setting up the build process using CC.NET.
- Solely responsible for maintaining and extending the audio code (using FMOD).
- Responsible for the two ships (Raptor & Marauder) released as DLC, experimenting with different gameplay mechanics and balancing the ships.
- Bug fixing across the code base, including debugging Lua scripts, particularly in the run up to launch.

doublesix games

September 2010 - January 2012 (Holiday Employment)

- Developed Xed in C#; the tool used for creating levels, prefabs and other resources for Xii (the in house game engine).
- Created an editor for the in house particle system.
- Created a visual material editor where you could assemble shaders in either CG and HLSL out of a tree of nodes;
 similar to the one found in Unreal Development Kit.

Projects

Third Year Project - Component based AI Tool

July 2013 - June 2014 (in progress)

- Final year project designed and developed independently.
- **C#** application to create Al behaviours from a network of smaller behaviours, code behaviours and functions.
- I wanted to create a tool which would allow designers the ability to construct AI behaviours without having to deal with coding and low level issues such as physics. This was inspired by the AI code in Strike Suit Zero, and designers frustration at the fact that any changes had to be written by coders.
- Creating an example game in **Unity3D** to demonstrate different Als that can be created in the tool.

"Pub?" - Android App for organising a trip to the pub

January 2012 - March 2012

- Competition run by Atos to design and make an app under the theme "Smart Mobility".
- Out of 80 original teams from across the globe we finished fourth.
- I was Project Manager of our five person team. We made an **Android** app in **Java** for organising trips to the pub.
- The app ranked your friends based off your Facebook activity, current locations and history to try and predicted whether you would want to invite them to the pub.
- Involved giving a presentation to a board of senior Atos employees about the app and its development.

Multiple "48 Hour Game Jams"

2009 - 2013

- Involved making a game in less than 48 hours, with a team of people met at the event.
- Used a wide variety of technologies including **Unity**, **UDK**, **XNA** and **Flash**.
- Games I have made include:
 - o 2013 "Disaster Mode" a game about managing the aftermath of a pandemic. Made in XNA.
 - 2012 "Gloop" a racing game in which your track you took the previous lap forms the next lap. This was my
 first time using the Unreal Development Kit.
 - o 2011 "And Then the Lights Went Out" a game where you had to divert light through prisms to feed your planet. This was my first experience using the **Unity** game engine.

Portfolio

You can read more about the various projects I have done at http://www.tkiley.co.uk.

Other Interests

In my spare time I develop personal projects and games, particularly in **Unity**. I also frequent StackOverflow (http://stackoverflow.com/users/958004/t-kiley), enjoying finding new problems and helping people solve them. I have used a number of different IDEs, including Visual Studio, and several source control solutions, including Perforce and Git.

I take a great deal of pleasure in studying mathematics, even (in fact, particularly) when it is completely abstract and seemingly unusable! I like to go cycling during the weekends. When I can, I love going to gigs. Naturally, I play a lot of games and have recently been enjoying Prison Architect and Skyrim.

References

Mark Sinclair (Technical Director)

Born Ready Games
81 Walnut Tree Close
Guildford
GU1 4UH
mark.sinclair@bornreadygames.com

Ranko Lazic (Personal Tutor & Lecturer)

Department of Computer Science University of Warwick Coventry CV4 7AL R.S.Lazic@warwick.ac.uk